

PRAVISHA SINGH

SEO EXECUTIVE | TEAM LEADER

CONTACT

+91 - 9131455717

pravisha2singh@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pravis ha-singh-a5b71a186

Bhilai, Chhattisgarh

SKILLS

- On Page SEO
- OFF Page SEO
- · Content Writing
- C Programming Basics
- HTML, CSS, WordPress Basic Knowledge
- · Social Media Management
- Link Building

TOOLS

- MOZ
- Screaming Frog
- Search Console
- Ahrefs / SEMRush
- ChatGPT
- RankMath
- Grammarly
- Canva
- Google Adwords
- Google Analytics
- MS Office

EDUCATION

B.Com

SSSMV, Bhilai

Year 2017-2020

M.Com

M J College, Bhilai

Year 2020-2022

MBA (HR & Systems)

SSTC, Bhilai

Year 2021-2023

PROJECTS

- EmpMonitor
- SocioBoard
- PowerAdSpy
- MailGaze
- Socinator
- ManGazeAstroLive
- Codesamour
- AdsGPT
- 24/7 Locksmith
- Saastrac
- Haider Carpet Cleaning
- Passion8Press
- Australian Opal Cutters

PROFILE

I am a highly passionate individual with 5+ years of experience who thrives upon seeking new challenges through my career as a SEO Executive/Specialist. My initial years of working in the business industry push me to go further in discovering more things in it. Of course, I am motivated to join a group of seasoned and experienced SEO professionals in the industry respectively.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Media Executive | Team Leader

Globussoft Technologies Pvt Ltd

2020 - Present

- Lead and mentored a team, setting KPIs and managing resources.
- Hiring candidates, conducting interview for SEO Link Building & Content Writing.
- Conducted thorough keyword research to identify high-traffic and relevant keywords for website optimization.
- Implemented strategic placement of keywords in meta tags, headers, and content to enhance search engine visibility.
- Performed SEO Audit for Inhouse & Client Projects
- Helped to create and support marketing content to socialize and use for social media purposes (e.g. Customer video briefs, customer case studies, blog posts, posts from analysts and customers)
- Executed successful link-building campaigns to acquire high-quality backlinks from authoritative websites.
- Integrated social media strategies to increase brand visibility and drive traffic. Managed social media accounts to foster engagement and sharing.
- Created and promoted high-quality, shareable content to attract natural backlinks.
- Recommended changes to website architecture, content, linking and other factors to improve SEO positions for target keywords.
- Handled social media pages of inhouse projects to build its presence amongst audience.
- Awarded as "Employee Of The Year" & "Best Performer Of The Year" at Globussoft

Content Writer (On-The Job Internship)

Globussoft Technologies Pvt Ltd

2021 - 45 Days

- Written content for various blogs and learned tips & tricks about content writing.
- · Learned about keyword research.
- Grabbed complete knowledge on how to write SEO-friendly content
- · Web Content Writing, Writing, and Proofreading skills
- · Experience in Content Strategy and Research
- · Strong understanding of social media trends and practices
- Review and revise content for grammar, clarity, and consistency while maintaining academic integrity and proper citation.

Sole Proprietor Business Owner

2023 - Present

Midnight Meals (Bhilai, C.G.)